Hui-Ni Jane

Hsinchu, Taiwan 300 | +1864-392-3952 | whitney0721@gmail.com | https://WhitneyTheEducator.github.io

SUMMARY

TESOL graduate and 6+ years of experience educating ESOL students from elementary to adults. 1+ years of teaching experience in an American middle school. Focused on providing an innovative, fun, and inspiring classroom. Keep good relationships with students' parents regarding both academic grades and behaviors.

EDUCATION

Master of Teaching English as a Second Language (TESOL) | University of South Florida - Tampa, FL

01/2017-12/2018

- > Overall GPA: 4.0 | USF Academic Scholar
- Relevant Coursework: FL/ESOL Practicum | Cross-Culture Issue in Teaching ESOL | Current Trends in Foreign Language Education

Bachelor of English of Language and Literature | Chinese Culture University - Taipei, Taiwan

07/2012-07/2016

WORK EXPERIENCES

Chinese English Teacher | Kang Chiao International School – Hsinchu, Taiwan

08/2020- Present

- ➤ Teach Vocabulary, Grammar, Reading and Writing to 1st and 3rd grade
- > Developed curricula, and plan lessons and class activities
- Frequently examined and adjusted learning units and materials to meet students' need.
- > Routinely contact parents regarding students' performances as their homeroom teacher
- > Assist administration work

Mandarin Teacher | Village of Excellence Academy Middle School – Tampa, FL

01/2019 - 02/2020

- > Taught beginning and intermediate Chinese to 6th, 7th, and 8th grade as their homeroom teacher
- Developed curricula, and plan lessons and assessments
- Frequently examined and adjusted learning units and materials to meet students need.
- Assisted, monitored, evaluated, assessed and reported students learning performance through formative and summative assessments

Chinese Teacher Internship | Safety Harbor Middle School – Safety Harbor, FL

02/2018 - 04/2018

- > Observed and shadowed the class
- ➤ Helped the teacher prepare class materials
- ➤ Gave lessons to 6th, 7th and 8th graders.

INTO USF Lab Assistant | INTO University of South Florida – Tampa, FL

02/2018 - 12/2018

- ➤ Helped the instructors set up the classroom materials
- ➤ Made classroom reservations for instructors
- Fixed computer hardware for staff and instructors

Chinese Tutor | Tampa, FL

08/2017 - 05/ 2019

- ➤ Mentored English-speaking student in Mandarin
- Provided fun and interesting learning activities

English Tutor | Taoyuan, Taiwan

10/2013 - 08/ 2017

- ▶ Planned and delivered lessons to various students from elementary to adults
- Provided appropriate analysis and feedback on academic work
- > Evaluated student progress and prepare teaching plans according to their specific
- > Customized lesson materials to each level and improve their pronunciations and speaking skills.

Leadership

Class leader Chinese Culture University-Taipei, Taiwan

07/2012-06/2016

- Managed class meetings and recorded student attendance
- Assisted teachers in grading exams and organizing subject materials

Community Service

P.E.E.R Refugee Program Mentor | University of South Florida- Tampa, FL

02/2017-05/2017

- ➤ Provided instruction on several fundamental disciplines for refugee youth
- > Planned lessons and activities on English writing and reading, American History, and Math

SKILLS

➤ Highly proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint